A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Public Broadcasting, Office Files of David M. Davis FA687
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Public Broadcasting, Office Files of David M. Davis
1967-1973, bulk 1968
Rockefeller Archive Center
Davis, David M. (David McFarland), 1926-2007
Ford Foundation
FA687
3.93 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
Arranged in 2 series by file type.
Collection arrangement is as follows:
Series I. Television Grant Files, 1968
Series II. Subject Files, 1967-1973
Scope and Contents
Contains: Television Grant Files and Subject Files.
Biographical / Historical
David M. Davis (1926-2007) worked in public broadcasting for over forty years. In 1968, he joined the Ford Foundation as a Program Officer in the Foundation's Office of Public Broadcasting. He was later promoted to Officer in Charge of the program. Following a change in the Foundation's program structure, Davis became Officer in Charge of the Office of Communications.
Prior to joining the Ford Foundation, Davis had public broadcasting producer, director, and station manager positions in Philadelphia, East Lansing, Washington, D.C., Greensboro, and Boston. After he left the Ford Foundation, he worked as a consultant for the German Marshall Fund for a few years. He also served as President of Public Television Playhouse, Inc. (producer of the "American Playhouse" television series) and President and CEO of American Documentary, Inc. (producer of the "POV" television series).
Davis earned a bachelor's degree in musical education in 1947 from Northwestern University and a M.S. in 1951 from the University of Pennsylvania. Davis died in 2007.
- Television Grant Files, 1968; I
  Arrangement
  Alphabetical
  - Alabama ETV Network, 1968 (Box 1)
  - American Samoa, Pago Pago KVZK, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Arizona, Tempe KAET, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Arizona, Tucson KUAT, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Arkansas, Conway KETS, 1968 (Box 1)
  - California, Redding KIXE, 1968 (Box 1)
  - California, Sacramento KVIE, 1968 (Box 1)
  - California, San Bernardino, 1968 (Box 1)
  - California, San Diego KEBS, 1968 (Box 1)
  - California, San Jose KTEH, 1968 (Box 1)
  - California, San Mateo KCSM, 1968 (Box 1)
  - California, Santa Ana, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Central Educational Network, Inc., 1968 (Box 1)
  - Colorado, Denver KRMA, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Connecticut ETV Network, 1968 (Box 1)
  - District of Columbia (DC), Washington WETA, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Florida, Gainsville WUFT, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Florida, Miami WTHS, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Florida, Orlando WMFE, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Florida, Pensacola WSRE, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Florida ETV Network, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Florida, Tallahassee WFSU, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Florida, Tampa WEDU, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Florida, Tampa WUSF-TV, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Georgia, Athens WGTV, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Georgia, Atlanta WETV, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Hawaii, Honolulu KHET, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Idaho, Moscow KUID-TV, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Illinois, Carbondale WSIU-TV, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Illinois, Urbana WILL, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Indiana, Bloomington WTIU, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Indiana, St. John WCAE, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Indiana, Vincennes WVUT, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Kansas, Topeka WTWU, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Kentucky Authority for ETV, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Kentucky, Louisville WFPK, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Maine ETV Network, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Maine, Lewiston WCBB, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Maryland, Baltimore WMPB, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Michigan, Detroit WTVS, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Michigan, East Lansing WMSB, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Michigan, Marquette WNMR, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Michigan, Mt. Pleasant WCMU, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Michigan, University Center WUCM, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Midwestern Educational Television, Inc., 1968 (Box 1)
  - Illinois, Chicago WTTW, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Minnesota, Appleton KWCM, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Minnesota, Duluth WDSE, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Minnesota, St. Paul KTCA, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Mississippi, Jackson WMAA, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Missouri, Kansas City KCSD, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Nebraska ETV Network, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Nevada, Las Vegas KLVX, 1968 (Box 2)
  - New Mexico, Albuquerque KNME, 1968 (Box 2)
  - New York, Binghamton KSKG-TV, 1968 (Box 2)
  - New York, Buffalo WNED, 1968 (Box 2)
  - New York, New York WNYE, 1968 (Box 2)
  - New York, New York Municipal Broadcasting System, 1968 (Box 2)
  - New York, Rochester WXXI, 1968 (Box 2)
  - New York, Schenectady WMHT, 1968 (Box 2)
  - New York, Stamford, 1968 (Box 2)
  - New York, Syracuse (Liverpool) WCNY, 1968 (Box 2)
  - North Carolina ETV Network, 1968 (Box 2)
  - North Carolina, Charlotte WTVI, 1968 (Box 2)
  - North Dakota, Fargo KFME, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Ohio, Athens WOUB, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Ohio, Bowling Green WBGU, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Ohio, Cincinnati WCET, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Ohio, Columbus WOSU, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Ohio Educational Television Network, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Ohio, Newark WGSF, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Ohio, Oxford WMUB, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Ohio, Toledo WGTE, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Oklahoma ETV Network, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Oklahoma, Oklahoma City KOKH, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Oregon, Corvallis KOAP-TV/KOAC-TV (Box 2)
  - Pennsylvania, Bethlehem WLVT, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Pennsylvania, Philadelphia WHYY, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Pennsylvania, Scranton WVIA-TV, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Pennsylvania, University Park WPSX-TV, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Puerto Rico ETV Network, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Rhode Island, Providence WSBE-TV, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Rocky Mountain Public Broadcasting Network, 1968 (Box 2)
  - South Dakota, Brookings KESD-TV, 1968 (Box 3)
  - South Dakota, Rapid City KBHE, 1968 (Box 3)
  - South Dakota, Vermillion KUSD, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Southern Educational Communications Association, Inc. (Regional), 1968 (Box 3)
  - Tennessee Educational Television Network, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Tennessee, Knoxville WSJK-TV, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Tennessee, Memphis WKNO, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Tennessee, Nashville WDCN, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Texas, Dallas KERA, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Texas, Lubbock KTXT, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Texas, Richardson KRET, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Utah, Logan KUSU, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Utah, Ogden KOET, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Utah, Ogden KWCS, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Utah, Provo KBYU, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Utah, Salt Lake City KUED, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Vermont ETV Network, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Virginia, Norfolk WHRO, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Virginia, Richmond WCVE, 1968; Photos (Box 3)
  - Virginia, Roanoke WBRA, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Virginia, Staunton WPVT, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Washington, Pullman KWSC, 1968; Photos (Box 3)
  - Washington, Seattle KCTS, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Washington, Spokane KSPS, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Washington, Tacoma (Lakewood Center) KPEC, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Washington, Tacoma KTPS, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Washington, Yakima KYVE, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Western Educational Network, 1968 (Box 3)
  - West Virginia, Huntington WMUL, 1968 (Box 3)
  - West Virginia, Morgantown WWVU, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Wisconsin, Madison WHA (Box 3)
  - Wisconsin, Milwaukee WMVS, 1968 (Box 3)
- Subject Files, 1967-1973; II
  - Children and Television Seminar, 1973 September 17-19 (Box 3)
  - Electronic Communications -- Public Policy Issues and Research Activities, 1967 October (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation -- Noncommercial Television, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Jones, Ken, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, David M. Davis, 1968 (Box 3)